♪♪（太鼓）
Tailed Beast Counting Song!
All right, here we go!
（ナルト）『尾獣数え唄』
はじまり　はじまり！
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku.
ONE TAIL SHUKAKU / GAARA
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku.
♪♪「一つ　人より
居眠り守鶴」
Two, burning in fire, Matatabi.
TWO TAIL MATATABI / YUGITO NI'I
♪♪「二つ　ファイヤー
燃えてる又旅」
Three, leave the water to Isobu.
THREE TAIL ISOBU / YAGURA
♪♪「三つ　水なら
任せろ磯撫」
Four, hot as lava, Son Goku.
FOUR TAIL SONGOKU / ROSHI
♪♪「四つ　溶岩
あついぜ孫悟空」
Five, always on the run, Kokuo.
FIVE TAIL KOKUO / HAN
♪♪「五つ　いつでも
駆け足　穆王」
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken.
SIX TAIL SAIKEN / UTAKATA
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken.
♪♪「六つ　無理せず」
♪♪「アワてず犀犬」
Seven, the flying leaf insect, Chomei.
♪♪「七つ　ナナフシ　空飛ぶ重明」
SEVEN TAIL CHOMEI / FU
Seven, the flying leaf insect, Chomei.
Eight, "Yeah!" is all it needs, Gyuki.
♪♪「八つ　やっぱり」
EIGHT TAIL GYUKI / KILLER BEE
Eight, "Yeah!" is all it needs, Gyuki.
♪♪「ウィーだぜ　牛鬼」
Nine, "ko-kon" cries the mighty Kurama.
♪♪「九つ　ココンと
最強　九喇嘛」
NINE TAIL KURAMA / NARUTO UZUMAKI
Nine, "ko-kon" cries the mighty Kurama.
All the Tailed Beasts have
finally come together.
♪♪「とうとうそろった　尾獣の仲間」
They're a little hard,
but they're nice names.
♪♪「ちょい　ムズだけどいい名前」
They're all splendid names.
♪♪「みんな　立派な名前だね」
They're all wonderful names.
♪♪「みんな　すてきな名前だね」
お次は　人柱力！
いくってばよ！
Next up, the Jinchuriki!
Here we go!
GAARA
One, with terrible bags
under his eyes, Gaara.
♪♪「一つ　ひどい
クマだよ我愛羅」
♪♪「二つ　フニャ～ンと　猫なでユギト」
YUGITO NI'I
Two, with a silky voice like a cat, Yugito.
♪♪「三つ　水影
四代目のやぐら」
YAGURA
Three, the Fourth Mizukage, Yagura.
♪♪「四つ　４０年　四尾と老紫」
ROSHI
Four, together for forty years,
Four Tails and Roshi.
♪♪「五つ　いかついパワーのハン」
HAN
Five, tough and powerful, Han.
♪♪「六つ　無口な
着流しウタカタ」
UTAKATA
Six, reserved and dressed
in a kimono, Utakata.
♪♪「七つ　なごむッス　くのいちフウ」
FU
Seven, the heart-warming kunoichi, Fu.
♪♪「八つ　やばいよ
ラップのキラービー」
KILLER BEE
Eight, he's got crazy rap skills, Killer Bee.
♪♪「九つ　木ノ葉の
うずまきナルト」
NARUTO UZUMAKI
Nine, the Leaf's Naruto Uzumaki.
♪♪「とっても強い　人柱力のみんな」
All the powerful Jinchuriki
have finally come together.
♪♪「尾獣と仲良くなれるかな？」
Can they become friends
with the Tailed Beasts?
♪♪「みんな　立派な忍だね」
They're all splendid shinobi.
♪♪「みんな　すてきな忍だね」
They're all wonderful shinobi.
The Promise of Victory
– Heave…ho!
（２人）せ～の。
Hey, did you hear?
What?
Rumor is that Madara appeared
at the other battlefields.
Madara?
We're at war with him,
so that's nothing unusual.
（シュン）おい　聞いたか？
（ナツ）何をだ？
（シュン）他の戦場じゃあ
マダラが　現れたって話だぜ。
No! I'm not talking about that
shady-looking masked Madara.
（ナツ）マダラ？　そりゃ
そいつと戦争してんだから→
They're saying the real one appeared!
現れても
別に　おかしくはねえだろ。
What?!
What do you mean, "real one"?
（シュン）違えよ！　あのうさんくせえ
仮面のマダラじゃなくて→
本物が出たって話だよ！
Are you saying, that all this time,
he's been a fake?
（ナツ）あ？　おいおい。
No, what I mean is…
A super strong one,
本物って　いったいなんだよ？
just like the real Madara Uchiha
has appeared!
じゃあ　今までのは
偽物だったっていうのか？
And he's strong enough
to take on the Five Kage.
（シュン）そうじゃなくて！
マジで→
Take on the Five Kage?
うちはマダラくらい
すげえ強えのが出たって話！
Give me a break.
It's true!
五影を相手に　互角以上だってよ。
From what I heard,
五影が相手？　またまた～。
he hurled down meteorites
and created a jungle instantly.
ほんとだって！
Above all, he's a giant…
tens of meters tall.
俺の聞いた話じゃ
隕石を　ドッカンドッカン降らせたり→
一瞬で　ジャングルを作ったり→
A giant?!
何より　身の丈数十メートルの
巨人だって話だぞ。
Well, they're just rumors…
巨人？
Will you two cut it out?!
ハハハハ…。
Sure, the enemy's numbers
have dwindled.
だから　噂だって。
（ネジ）お前ら　いいかげんにしろ！
But we need to hunt down
the remaining enemy.
確かに　この戦場の敵は
残りわずか。
We're on a mission here.
Get serious!
しかし　その残党退治とはいえ
戦争中だ。
Focus on the enemy,
here and now!
S-Sorry…
少しは　緊張感を持て！
You're right!
今は　目の前の敵に集中しろ！
We weren't able to show
our stuff at this battle.
す　すみません。
そうっすね。
We'll show 'em on
the next battlefield!
この戦場じゃ　たいした手柄を
立てられなかったし…。
Okay.
次の戦場で暴れてやりますよ！
うむ…。
I'll pursue the enemy on the left!
You guys go to the right and
stop any remnants there!
Roger!
（ネジ）俺は　左を追う！
– Let's go!
– Yeah!
お前たちは　右のを仕留めてくれ！
（２人）はい！
いくぜ！
おうよ！
Another one bites the dust.
ぐわっ！
Hey! I'm the one that got him!
ヘヘ　一丁あがり。
おい　こいつをやったのは俺だろ。
What? Trying to take
all the credit?
Well, all you did was use
a little jutsu at the very end!
（シュン）なんだよ
手柄を独り占めする気か？
（ナツ）そっちこそ　最後にちょろっと
術　使っただけじゃねえか！
And that's what did him in!
Fine, I'll give you that…
（シュン）はあ？
それが　決め手だったよな！
（ナツ）百歩　譲って
そうだったとしてもだ！
But catching one weakling
is nothing to brag about.
って　ザコ１匹　競っても
しようがねえか。
だな。
Yeah…
Eight Trigrams: Air Palm!
ぐわっ！
（ネジ）八卦空掌！
Watch out, you two!
Are you all right?!
気をつけろ　２人とも！
You saved us…
大丈夫か？
た　助かりました。
The battle here finally ended.
やっと　この戦場での戦いも
終わるってのに→
If we were to get killed
when it was all over…
We were about to be humiliated…
最後の最後に
やられたんじゃ…。
シャレにならないとこでした…。
The next battle is going
to be on the front lines.
次の戦場は
いよいよ前線だからな。
SHINOBI
《シカク：うむ…　マダラは
五影が抑えていてくれる。
The Five Kage are
holding back Madara.
Sending Kakashi and Guy
out ahead
カカシとガイを先行させた策も
はまったようだ。
seems to have worked.
However, Naruto and the others
on the front line
それでも前線のナルトたちは
押され気味。
are under pressure.
Once the other battles wind down,
they'll rush to lend support.
だが　各戦場のケリがつきしだい
あいつらが駆けつける》
ん？　大丈夫か？
Are you all right?!
Y-Yes… I'm sorry.
はい…　すみません。
Compared to the others fighting
on the battlefield,
戦場で戦っている方々に
比べれば→
I have it easy, and yet…
自分なんて　楽なほうなのに。
No. We have our own kind of tension
that we have to contend with here.
いや…　ここには
ここにしかない緊張感もある。
Don't be so hard on yourself.
気にすることはない。
This is a critical time for us.
大事なときです。
大丈夫です！
I'm okay!
そうか…　すまないな。
All right. Thanks.
みんな　聞いてくれ！
Listen up, everyone!
The war is entering its final stage!
戦争も最終局面へ
向かいつつある！
すべての部隊の頭である
俺たちが　ミスをおかしては→
We are the central command center
for every company.
We cannot afford to make
a single mistake!
大事に至る！
無理をするなとは言えない。
I can't tell you not to overdo it.
だが　もう少しだ！
踏ん張ってほしい！
But hang in there a bit longer
and do your best!
頼む！
I'm counting on you!
（青）感知部隊には　この程度で
音を上げる者などいない。
There isn't a man
in the Sensory Unit
who'd throw in the towel
with something like this!
なあ　みんな！
（みんな）おう！
Right, guys?!
– Right!
おっ…
俺たちだって　そうですよ！
Neither would we!
That goes for us too!
ね？　いのいち隊長！
Right, Captain Inoichi?!
通信部隊は疲れ知らず。
それを見せてやりましょうよ！
Let's show 'em that
the Communications Unit is tireless!
（いのいち）うむ…　そうだな。
Hmm…
疲れたら　俺がフォローしてやるから
少しくらいなら休んでも…。
Right…
But if you get tired,
I'll take over…
だ～っ！　そこはビシッと→
so it's okay to rest a bit.
俺についてこいで
いいじゃないっすか！
Huh?! Don't take it easy on us!
空気読んでくださいよ！
Just tell us to follow you!
You have to learn to
go with the flow!
Sorry… I'm not good at
that kind of stuff.
すまんな…。
そういうのは　苦手だ。
That erased the pent-up anxiety
everyone was feeling…
《今ので　必要以上に
張り詰めていた緊張感がとれ→
and a sense of unity was born
at Headquarters.
本部に一体感が生まれた。
Headquarters, each battle company,
本部と各部隊
そして前線で戦うナルトたち。
and Naruto and the others fighting
on the front lines.
If we can stand united in purpose,
みんなの思いを
ひとつにできれば　この戦争…。
our foundation will be unshakeable
and we can overcome this war.
盤石の体制で
乗り切ることができる！》
ん？
Th-This is…?!
こ　これは…。
どうした！？
What happened?
– Tailed Beast Bomb!
（ナルト／九尾）尾獣玉！
いよいよ前線か…。
The front line at last…
待ってろよ　俺の手柄。
Just you wait!
I'll show you my stuff!
んっ　なんだ！？
Huh?! What is that?
（ナツ）な…　何が起きてるんだ？
What's happening?!
あれは前線のほうだな。
Isn't that in the direction
of the front line?
え？　あ　あそこに…。
これから行くのか。
Huh? L-Look over there.
Is that where we're going?
（ネジ）うむ…　さっきのマダラの話→
Yes…
That talk earlier about Madara…
噂話では
なかったのかもしれんな。
Maybe they weren't just rumors.
でかい手柄がありそうだぜ…。
That looks like…
（シュン）おお…　今度こそ手柄を。
something huge…
Yeah… Here's our chance
to show 'em.
Well done, Naruto!
I never thought you’d be able
to completely control Nine Tails.
（八尾）よくやったぞ　ナルト！
（マダラ）九尾まで
完全に　コントロール下に置くとはな。
However, it looks like you still can’t
maintain it for too long.
だが…
まだ　長続きはしないようだ。
So same old, same old.
それで　今までどおりだ。
It's not the same old, same old…
今までどおりじゃねえ…。
I just learned a whole bunch
of hard names all at once!
難しい名前　一度にたくさん
教えてもらったからよ！
Difficult names?
（マダラ）難しい名前だと？
What does that have to do
with anything?
それが　何だというのだ？
You don't know, do you?!
はぁ～ん…
お前は知らねえんだな！？
へっ！
I'm not gonna tell you!
べ～。　教えてやんねえよ！
Naruto gaining
such experience and strength
（ガイ）ナルトが　これほど成長したのを
目の当たりにすると…。
makes me feel old and feeble.
自分が　ずいぶんと
老いぼれに感じるな…。
What's the matter?
（カカシ）どうしたの？　いつもの
お前らしくないじゃない。
You're not being yourself!
It may sound funny
coming from me…
俺が言うのも　なんだけど…。
The springtime of our youth
is still far from over!
俺たちの青春も→
まだ　終わっちゃいないってことで
いかないか？
We still have a lot of…
俺たちは　ここへ来て　まだ…。
Quiet! Do you want to make me
feel even worse?
それ以上　言うな！
余計　むなしくなる。
That's the Guy I know!
それでこそ　ガイだ。
《あの顔…》
That expression…
《ん…　汗？》
Huh? Am I sweating?
《いや…　雨だ。
No, it's just rain.
俺が　あんなやつら相手に→
These fools could never
make me sweat.
汗を流すことなど
あるはずがない。
ナルトは　ただのサスケへの当て馬…。
Naruto was always
merely a pawn to test Sasuke.
俺にとっては
余興でしかないガキだったはず。
That brat's supposed to be
an amusement.
あいつの力は把握していた…。
I knew what his limits were.
この違和感は
力から　くるものではない…。
There's no way his power could be
pushing me this hard.
なら　何だというのだ！？
So what is it?!
いったい　何が…！？》
What's happened?
《いや…
そんなことは　どうでもいい。
It doesn't matter.
ナルトが何者かなんて
どうでもいいことだ…》
It doesn't matter who
or what Naruto is now…
この戦争より後
過去も未来もない…。
After this war is over,
存在すらも…
すべてが無意味になる。
there will be no past or future.
Nothing that exists now
will matter then!
A-Amazing…
Did you guys feel that?
（青）す…　すごいな…。
I can't believe it.
お前ら　今のを感じたか！？
There's no doubt.
That is the Nine Tails' power!
信じられませんよ…　間違いない。
Yeah…
あれが　九尾の力ですよ！
ああ…。
But I sense something…
slightly different.
《だが…　それとは少し違う
何かを感じる…》
What's the current situation?
その後の状況は？
Naruto Uzumaki is holding back
the Masked Madara
うずまきナルトが
とんでもない力で→
with an unbelievable amount
of power.
面のマダラを押さえてる…。
ありえないチャクラだ。
The chakra is unbelievable!
He's keeping him at bay.
いや…　むしろ　押してる。
It's just the four of them!
Naruto, Lord Bee, Kakashi and Guy!
ビー殿　カカシ殿　ガイ殿を含め
たった４人で…。
Inoichi!
Relay Naruto's actions directly
into the minds
いのいち！　ありったけの力で
このナルト側の状況を→
of the reinforcement troops
with everything you've got!
増援部隊全員の頭の中に
直接　語りかけてくれ！
Fifteen seconds is all we need!
１５秒でいい！
ここで　一気に士気を上げたい！
I want to boost everyone's morale
all at once!
Those four are giving it their all!
あいつら４人が
全力で　ふんばってる。
I want the rest of us here
to do everything we can too.
なら　ここは　ここでできることを
全力でするぞ！
Convey their resolve to everyone!
あいつらの思いを伝えるんだ！
To everyone?!
全員って…　そんなことをしたら→
It will overload the Chakra Network.
チャクラの経絡系に
負担がかかりすぎて…。
Make one mistake and…
下手すると…。
フッ　ムチャを言う…。
You ask for the extreme.
Make it ten seconds!
１０秒だ！
いのいちさん！
Master Inoichi!
すまない…
だが　今　大切なことだ！
Sorry, but this is critical!
Make it short,
but make it count!
短い分　上手くまとめてくれよ。
口は上手いほうじゃないが
任せとけ！
I'm not good with words,
but you can count on me!
《本部より伝達！
Message from HQ!
増援ポイントにて　状況優勢！
We have the upper hand at
the battle reinforcement point!
つまり　うずまきナルトが
ふんばってくれてる！
Naruto Uzumaki is standing firm!
俺たち　連合が守るべき
ナルトが　ビー殿が！
The ones we must protect at all costs,
Naruto and Lord Bee…
前線で　強い思いを持って
戦ってくれてる！
are fighting with everything
they've got on the front line!
ガイも　カカシも同じくだ！
Guy and Kakashi are there too!
そして　連合のみんなも
その強い思いに加わってくれ。
To everyone in the Allied Force…
I need all of you to add to
their mighty hearts!
その　みんなの強い思いが…》
Amplify it with your mighty hearts!
《この戦争の　勝利への予言だ！》
I promise you, victory is now!
ガハッ…　ハァ　ハァ…。
やっぱ…　口下手だな　俺は。
I'm bad with words, after all.
結局２０秒も…　かかっちまった…。
It took me 20 seconds.
ハァ　ハァ…。
隊長…。
《ああ…。
Captain…
それが　お前の思いの強さだ》
Yeah…
That just shows how mighty
your heart is…
ハァ　ハァ…　すまねぇ…。
ハァ　ハァ…。
Sorry…
《ヒナタ：ナルト君…
私は　あなたをずっと…。
Naruto…
ずっと…　ずっと追いかけてきた。
I've run, and run after you
my whole life.
そして　今も追いかけてる》
And I'm still running after you.
《でも　この戦争が終わったら→
もう　あなたを
追いかけるのはやめにします。
But when this war is over.
次は　ナルト君の横にいて→
I'm going to stop running.
しっかり
あなたの手を握ったまま→
I'll stand with you.
I'll hold your hand.
同じ歩幅で歩きたいんです。
待っていてください》
And I'll walk with you by your side.
《キバ：ナルト　お前にゃ　昔から
しっかり　マーキングしといたんだ。
So please wait for me!
Naruto…
俺のライバルとしてよ。
I marked you as
my rival ages ago.
俺が駆けつけるまで
マダラの相手は頼んだぜ！》
《シノ：俺の忍術で
ナルトを完璧にサポートする。
Hang tight against Madara,
until I get there!
なぜなら　…は必要ない！》
I'll support you completely
with my ninjutsu, Naruto.
（シカマル）うまくやってるようだな
ナルトのやつ。
And a reason…
is not necessary!
あいつのことだ…
ムチャやってる以外→
想像つかねえが　ああ見えて
実は　頭がキレるほうだからな。
Naruto is doing a good job.
I can't see him being
anything other than
（チョウジ）ナルトは　バカで　僕は　デブ
ってのがお決まりだったけど→
意外と　そうじゃなかったり
するんだよね。
《待っててね　ちょいバカナルト。
すらっとチョウジが今行くよ！》
冷静に
策を練るタイプじゃないけどな。
《だからこそ　俺がいる。
待ってろ　ナルト　もうすぐ行く！》
《いの：父さん　ありがとう。
ナルトの強い思いってのを
父さんがみんなに伝えてくれた。
その予言　必ず実現させなきゃ！》
《テンテン：ガイ先生　大丈夫かな？
ちゃんと　ナルトを
守ってあげてるかな？
カカシ先生もいることだし
大丈夫だと思うけど》
（サイ）雨が降っていなければ
超獣偽画で飛んでいけたのに！
（リー）文句より
スピードアップですよ　サイさん！
ガイ先生の勇姿
ナルト君の勇姿に応え→
己を貫き通すときです！
うん。
《これが仲間っていう感覚。
今の僕には
もう　はっきりとわかるよ。　ナルト》
《サクラ：ナルト
あんたは　木ノ葉を救った。
そして　今度は
忍の世界を救おうとしている。
いつもいつも
こんな大変なことばっかり→
任されることになっちゃってる。
でも　今度は　あんたが
何を言おうが一緒に…。
私だけじゃない。
今度こそ
みんなで一緒に戦おう！》
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
豆助　きょうのお魚は
今が旬のあれよ
＜　その魚とは…＞
＜　それは身が厚い皮で
覆われていることから→